# **Xiating Cai (John)**

Linkedin.com/in/JohnXiating

Phone: 0405 359 825 Email: john.xiating@gmail.com Portfolio: johnx.co

After travelling across the US, UK, South Asia and the east coast of Australia, and having worked in Shanghai and Sydney, I fell in love with Tasmania - a peaceful place to settle and create. I have experience in IT roles including Services Operations, Customer Support, Business Analysis, as well as experience across the Education and Digital Learning industry. I am currently living in Hobart, Tasmania. Whilst waiting for the approval of my 485 Post-Study Work Visa (currently in progress) a Bridging-A Visa has been granted allowing me to work full time unrestricted.

### **Education**

The University of Tasmania – Master of Information Management and Systems

March 2019 – December 2020

The University of Taizhou (Eastern China) – Bachelor of Physics (Teacher Education)

September 2008 – June 2012

## **Key Attributes**

**Interpersonal Skills**: Effectively collaborated across different business functions (product, service, and tech team) during two years of IT consulting roles with large complex global corporations in Shanghai, one year of Customer IT Support role in Australia, and volunteer work in California (USA).

**Digital Learning:** Experienced in E-learning having gained two years of working experience as a science teacher, one year of PASS leader (Web & Software Development) / Tutor at UTAS, two years of IT Consultant roles in digital learning platform italki.com (Shanghai). Familiar with learning management systems and tools such as D2L Brightspace, PebblePad, Echo360, digital learning platforms including Udemy, Coursera, and italki.

**Initiative & Teamwork:** Started up the <u>Virtual-study Hub</u> project to help students to study online during the COVID-19 time; Co-founded the <u>Multi-Cultural Club</u>, an active University society; Delivered award-winning team projects in GovHack 2020 and UHack 2019.

## **Work Experience**

Casual UConnect Support | Student Services, University of Tasmania

(Feb 2021 – Present)

- Gathered the students' inquires including payment, timetable, enrollment and account issues at the student services centre, answered and redirected students to the specific services on campus.
- · Managed and maintained students' information through the Client Services Officer Student Management and IdentityONE system.

#### IT Helpdesk / Administrator | Techbyte Solutions Launceston, Tasmania (Dec 2019 – Feb 2021)

- Offered IT services including remote IT support, video conferencing support, configuring networks and installing systems to organisations and individual customers with a range of technical understanding.
- Utilised JavaScript, CSS3, Bootstrap, Facebook developer tools to create a business website (techbyte.net.au).

#### PASS Leader | Student Retention & Success, University of Tasmania (Jan 2020 – Dec 2020)

- Designed both online and offline Peer Assisted Study Sessions (Web & Software Development) based on the students' feedback and needs. See session details here.
- · Facilitated and held online sessions for a range of different university students through MyLO student learning portal, Blackboard Collaborate, and Echo 360.

#### Residential Leader | Student Living Communities, University of Tasmania (Jan 2020 – Dec 2020)

· Assisted residents on-campus to use the student learning & living portal to improve their academic and university living experience, organised events with the student living team.

#### Tutor | Riawunna, University of Tasmania

(Mar 2020 – May 2020)

• Utilised presentation, video, audio to deliver the Chinese language tutorial for students in the Riawunna program via MyLO, Blackboard Collaborate, and Zoom video conference.

#### Udemy Instructor | Udemy.com

(Jan 2019 – Jan 2020)

 Developed a content-driven video course for learners on Udemy that reached 893 students across the world from 90 countries. Communicated with online students on the platform through the instructor dashboard. See course details at Udemy: Learn Chinese From Scratch.

#### Teacher IT Consultant | Services Management, italki Shanghai, China (Jul 2015 – May 2018)

- Provided consulting and IT support for online language teachers worldwide, posted monthly teacher newsletters and guides to 4000+ teachers on the platform.
- Undertook customer satisfaction research and data analysis through the ticketing system to improve the new teacher onboarding experience and student learning experience.

# **Projects and Volunteer Experience**

#### Web Developer & Co-founder | Multi-Cultural Club, Tasmania

(Jun 2020 - Present)

- · Co-Founded Multi-Cultural Club, utilised HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, and Bootstrap to create a static, informational website (mcctas.com.au) that met the needs of the society.
- · Captured and edited photos, images, videos for the event marketing, logo, and poster design.

Web Developer | Engineering Heritage Tasmania, Australia

(Jul 2020 - Oct 2020)

 Developed enhancements to the <u>EHTAS</u> website application (map tours) as discussed with the client. Created <u>guide documents</u> and <u>video guides</u> to assist members with ranges of technical knowledge.

### Project Leader | GovHack Launceston, Tasmania

(Aug 2020 – Aug 2020)

· Created the Heritage Hunt project concept, led and collaborated the team won three awards in <u>GovHack 2020</u>. Designed the UI and improved the prototype for the <u>Heritage Hunt app</u>. See project details <u>here</u>.

#### Project Leader | UHack Launceston, Tasmania

(Aug 2019 – Sep 2019)

- · Created the Plastic Free Tasmania project, led the team "No Plus" won the 3rd prize in the Student Division in UHack 2019 Competition.
- · Presented a pitch that highlighted the plastic problem and the solution of "Plastic Currency".

### Referees

Jacob Workman Head, Student Living Communities (North & Northwest)

University of Tasmania Email: Jacob.Workman@utas.edu.au Ph: 03 6324 3014

**Dr Kathy French** PASS Program Coordinator

University of Tasmania Email: Kr.French@utas.edu.au Ph: 03 6226 5546

Winyu Chinthammit Degree Coordinator, Human Interface Technology (HIT Lab AU)

University of Tasmania Email: Winyu.Chinthammit@utas.edu.au Ph: +61 3 6324 3975

Mark Smith Managing Director

Techbyte Solutions Email: Mark@Techbyte.net.au Ph: 03 6312 5190

Kellie Brandenburg Student Engagement Coordinator

University of Tasmania Email: Kellie.Brandenburg@utas.edu.au Ph: 03 6324 9701

**Sally Fuglsang** Peer Program, Leadership and Volunteering Team Leader

University of Tasmania Email: Sally.Fuglsang@utas.edu.au Ph: 03 6226 1902

Recommendations on LinkedIn: Linkedin.com/in/JohnXiating